techstartups.com 2016-12-03

# Privacy Policy | TechStartups.com

TechStartups.com Privacy Policy

Thank you for visiting the TechStartups.com Web site (hereinafter “the Site” or “TechStartups.com”) and reviewing our Privacy Policy, effective May 27, 2016. We take your privacy very seriously and are committed to safeguarding your privacy online. Please read the following policy to understand how your personal information will be treated as you use TechStartups.com.

Overview

This Privacy Policy (hereinafter “Policy”) governs your use of TechStartups.com and describes the information we collect from you and what may happen to that information. For example, this Policy will let you know what information we collect from you; what cookies are and how they are used; how your information is used; who is collecting your information; with whom your information may be shared; what options are available to you regarding collection, use, and distribution of your information; the types of security precautions in place to protect against loss, misuse, or alteration of your information; how we protect children’s privacy; and what else you should know about your online privacy.

Please note that we review our privacy practices from time to time, and that our practices are subject to change. We ask that you bookmark and periodically review this page to ensure continuing familiarity with the most current version of our Privacy Policy. All amended terms shall be automatically effective after they are posted on the Site.

By visiting the Site, you agree to be bound by the terms and conditions of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use or access the Site.

What Personally Identifiable Information does TechStartups.com collect?

Generally, TechStartups.com collects personally identifiable information in three (3) ways.

1\. If you voluntarily email us.  
2\. If you voluntarily enter your information from one of our forms (Submit News, Advertise, Contact Us or any other forms on the Site).  
3\. If you voluntarily leave a comment for a post that requires your name and email.

It’s your decision whether you want to share personally identifiable information with us. We also collect personal information when you report a problem or issue. If you contact TechStartups.com, we may keep a record of that correspondence. Please note that registration is not required to view the Site. Wherever TechStartups.com collects personal information we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page.

What are IP Addresses and how does TechStartups.com use them?

When your web browser requests a web page from another computer on the Internet, such as TechStartups.com, it automatically gives that computer the address where it should send the information. This is called your computer’s “IP address.” (IP stands for “Internet protocol.”) For many users accessing the Internet, the IP address will be different every time you log on. We record the IP Addresses that access TechStartups.com along with related information such as your browser type and operating system. This information helps us, in part, learn about the geographical distribution of our website visitors and the technology they use to access our site so that we can improve our Site.

What are “cookies” and how does TechStartups.com use them?

Data collection devices, such as “cookies,” are used to store, and sometimes track, information about you. Generally, these cookies help provide personalized services and promote trust and safety. A cookie is a small file containing a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a web server and placed on your computer’s hard drive to assist us in providing our services. All pages on the Site where you are prompted to login or that are customizable request that you accept cookies. Cookies are only read by the server that placed them and are unable to execute any code or virus. Most cookies are “session cookies,” and are automatically deleted from your hard drive at the end of a session.

More specifically, we may use cookies to remind us of who you are in order to deliver to you a more personalized service. We also may use cookies to measure your visiting patterns in the aggregate. We use this data to understand how our users’ habits are similar or different from one another so that we can make each new experience on TechStartups.com a better one. We may also use this information to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that you and other users will see on our Site. You are always free to decline our cookies if you wish and if your browser permits.

How does TechStartups.com use my information?

TechStartups.com uses your information to communicate with you if you contacted us. We may also use your personal information if we need to contact you; resolve disputes; troubleshoot problems; help promote safe interactions; detect and protect against error, fraud, or other criminal activity; and enforce our Terms of Service Agreement. We may also contact you about new information pertaining to TechStartups.com, additional services that we may offer, announcement for partnership or change in ad rates or availability.

Who is collecting information?

When you are using the Site and you voluntarily provide your for personal information, you are sharing that information with TechStartups.com alone, unless we specifically state otherwise. We do not sell or rent your information to third parties.

Please be advised that TechStartups.com does have advertisers, sponsors, or Web sites that have links on our Site may collect personally identifiable information about you when you interact with them. The information practices of those Web sites linked to TechStartups.com are not covered by this privacy statement and you should be sure to check the policies of those Web sites to before disclosing your personal information to them.

With whom does TechStartups.com share my information?

We understand that your privacy is important. Generally, TechStartups.com will not disclose your personally identifiable information unless we have your permission or under special circumstances, such as those described below.

When the Law Requires it: If we receive a subpoena, court order, or other legal process that requires that we disclose information about a User, we have no choice but to comply with it and will disclose the required information.

Third Party Data & Data in the Aggregate: Aggregate data (data gathered across all user accounts) may be gathered in a non-personally identifiable form to build higher quality, more useful online services by performing statistical analyses of the collective characteristics and behavior of our visitors, and by measuring demographics and interests regarding specific areas and services of the Site. Aggregate data may be disclosed in a non-personally identifiable manner to advertisers and other third parties for their marketing and promotional purposes. However, no personal information that could be used to identify you personally is disclosed in these situations.

External Service Providers: Separate services are offered by third parties, also known as external service providers, some of whom advertise on the Site. If you choose to use these services, disclose information to these parties, and/or grant them permission to collect information about you, their privacy policy governs the use of your information. We will not disclose your personal information to external service providers without your express consent.

Business Transaction: TechStartups.com reserves the right to transfer any and all information that we collect from visitors, or that we otherwise collect concerning or in connection with the Site, to a third party in the event of a sale or other transfer of assets or of any portion of our business. In the event TechStartups.com enters a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information may be among the assets transferred.

Other: We may disclose account information where we have reason to believe that disclosing the information is necessary to identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be violating TechStartups.com’s Terms of Service Agreement or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) TechStartups.com’s rights or property, other Site users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. TechStartups.com may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service, and improve our services.

We cannot ensure that all of your private communications and other personal information will never be disclosed in ways not otherwise described in this Policy. For example, as stated above, we may be forced to disclose information to the government or third parties under certain circumstances, third parties may unlawfully intercept or access transmissions or private communications, or users may abuse or misuse your personal information that they collect from the Site. We use industry standard practices to protect your privacy, however, we do not promise, and you should not expect, that your personal information or private communications will always remain private.

What are my choices regarding collection, use, and distribution of my information?

You do not have to disclose personally identifiable information to view the Site. TechStartups.com may also send you email from time to time if you did provide us with your information. Only TechStartups.com, or agents working on behalf of TechStartups.com, will send you these emails.

We do not tolerate spam. You are not licensed to add us, or a TechStartups.com User, even one who contacted you, to your mail (email or physical mail) list without the express, written consent of that User.

What security precautions are in place to protect the loss, misuse, or alteration of my information?

If you choose to share your email address or your personal information with third parties, you are responsible for all actions taken and therefore you should review that third party’s privacy policy. Whenever TechStartups.com handles your personal information, we take steps to ensure that your information is treated securely and in accordance with the relevant Terms of Service Agreement and this Policy. We use procedural and mechanical safeguards to protect your personal information against loss or theft as well as unauthorized access and disclosure to protect your privacy. Unfortunately, however, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. We cannot, therefore, warrant or ensure the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

How are children’s privacy protected?

TechStartups.com is not designed or intended for persons under the age of 13 and, if you are under the age of 13, you are not authorized to use the Site, submit information to TechStartups.com, or register with us. If you are between the age thirteen and eighteen, you may use the Site and register with us with the prior permission and authorization of your parent or guardian. Persons under the age of 13 are prohibited from viewing the Site, submitting any comments, or submitting any personal information to us, regardless of parental or guardian approval. We do not sell or rent personal information about any of our users, regardless of age.

Additional Information

Any questions regarding this statement should be directed to us through the use of our Contact page, which can be found at http://techstartups.com/contact-us/.

This Policy is the sole authorized statement of TechStartups.com’s practices with respect to the online collection of personally identifiable information and the usage of such information.
